# **METHA BABU**

#### WEB DEVELOPER

methababu@outlook.com

Skype id: methababukr +91 9344428777

#### SUMMARY:

Over 4.6 years of successful professional experience in Web Application Development
Over 4 years of solid programming experience on LAMP stack (Linux Apache MySQL Php)
Over 3 years of solid work experience on ,JavaScript , jQuery
Over 2 years of development experience in UI Programming.
Over 1+ years of development experience in Angular.

Strong Hands on development experience on Angularjs and Angular 2 + Strong Hands on experience on WordPress
Strong knowledge on SINGLE PAGE APPLICATION design using ANGULAR JS.
Strong knowledge on JavaScript, JQuery, Angular, Typescript
Strong Knowledge on HTML, CSS

Well experienced in using version control systems subversion (SVN), GIT.
Well experienced in using Developer tools (VS code IDE, NetBeans, Dreamweaver)
Strong knowledge of SEO

#### **EDUCATION:**

B.Tech Information Technology, Pannai college of engineering and Technology Sivagangai

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: - 4.6 Yrs

Client: Pichkaari design Studio, Jul 2017 - till date

Role : UI Developer

Tech Stack : HTML5 - CSS3 - WordPress - Angular - JQuery, JavaScript -- PHP

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for creating the look and feel of the public website
- Responsible for implementing functionality and responsive website.
- Creating the custom directives and making the reusable components

- Creating Angular services like Factory & Services
- Creating dynamic workflows using MXGraph lib.
- Consuming the REST APIs and showcasing the data to UI layer.

Client: Nbays IT Solusenz, Jun 2014 - Jun 2016

Role : Web Developer

Tech Stack : HTML5 - CSS3 - PHP - JQuery, JavaScript, WordPress

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for creating the look and feel of the public website
- Static and dynamic Websites and then Website Optimization
- SEO Optimization.

Client: Avolot Technologies, Jun 2013 - Jun 2014

Role : Web Developer

Tech Stack : Angular - PHP- HTML5-CSS-jquery, JavaScript

Responsibilities:

- Static Website and Dynamic website
- Create own content management system

Client: Blaze Web Service Jan 2013

Role : Trainee (6- Months Intern)

Tech Stack :PHP - html5 - css Product: Hotel Management system

### Responsibilities:

- Designing & Developing HTML5 layout with Responsive Web Development standards.
- Creating Custom components and integrating with application.
- Creating & Consuming REST APIs using PHP.
- Integrating third party OAuthentication

## Career Foot prints:

2013 Jan – 2013 Jun Web developer - Internship Blaze Web Services Madurai

2013 Jun – 2014 Aug Junior Web Developer Avolot Technologies Madurai

2014 Aug – 2017 Jun Web Developer Nbays It Solusenz Madurai

2017 Jun – Till date Web Developer Pichkaari Design Studio Bangalore